ublic final class MyResume implements Resume

JONATHAN TAYLOR

+12054347006

jontaylor091@gmail.com

Pelham, Alabama, 35124



github.com/Jtmonument



linkedin.com/in/jonathan-taylor-746ba8195/

SUMMARY

Diligent, detail-oriented, open-source-contributing computer science graduate with 7+ years of experience working with Java and 2+ years of experience working with frontend web technologies. I am a great listener with great interpersonal skills. I will put a smile on your face. Expect a faithful, moraleboosting self-learner eager to make an impact to all who rely on him.

PROJECTS

Open-source Algorithms

GitHub: TheAlgorithms/Java

Topological Sort PR #3060, JUnit5

List of Spring Projects

GitHub: Jtmonument/spring-repos

REST API with an MVC, Pet Clinic website, Web Application

McRonalds Restaurant Database

GitHub: Jtmonument/sql-database-project

Using MySQL and MySQL Workbench created a database with effective functions, triggers, and EER

Japan Travel Website

GitHub: Jtmonument/japan-travel-website

Using PHP, SQL, XAMPP, HTML, CSS, JS, I created the #1 UI in my class with good server-side scripting

EXPERIENCE

Web Developer / Master Troy University Computer Science Club **December 2021 - May 2022**

managing the Computer Science club website and club activities

Student AV / Tech Assistant Workship

January 2020 - September 2020

Troy University

Setting up technical equipment for university events

AuburnHackathon

February 2020

Auburn University

creating a game in C++ that enables players to disturb PC functionality

TrovHackathon

January 2020

Troy University Computer Science Department

team project working on frontend page templates for a pet adoption website

Cashier/Cook

June 2017 - Present

McAlister's Deli

serving guests with good customer service and faithfully preparing items on the menu

EDUCATION

Troy University

B.Sc. Computer Science

Minor in Cyber Security

August 2018 - May 2022

GPA: 3.3

RELEVANT COURSES

Software Engineering CS-3332-XTIA

SDLC, Scrum, Agile, loose coupling, DevOps, extreme programming, pair programming

Analysis of Algorithms CS-3329-TSAA

Time complexity, space complexity, dynamic programming, graph theory, shortest-path algorithms

Cyber Security Technique & Practice CS-4455-TSAA

VirtualBox, Kali Linux (virtual machine), nmap, pentbox (honeypot), iptables, pfSense, wireshark, snort (IDS), firewall-builder, scapy

Data Structures CS-3323-TSAA

Arrays, linked lists, stacks, queues, trees, binary search trees, searching and sorting algorithms

SKILLS

Programming Languages

- Java [Very Proficient] (7+ years of experience)
- **Python [Limited Proficiency]**

Soft Skills

- **Problem solving**
- Team-player
- Time management
- Intercultural
- **Excellent communication**
- **Object-Oriented Programming Design**
- **SOLID** principles
- French Language

Other technologies

- IntelliJ [Very Proficient] (5+ years of experience)
- Spring Framework (JPA, Web, HATEOAS & more)
- Maven
- **Unit Testing (JUnit)**
- Linux
- Selenium
- Frontend tech: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery
- Server-side tech: MySQL, PHP

CERTIFICATIONS

Coursera Certifications (no expiration date; all issued in June of 2022)

- **Introduction to DevOps**
- Introduction to Containers w/ Docker, Kubernetes & OpenShift
- **Introduction to Cloud Computing**
- **Getting Started with Git and GitHub**